essence.eu 2017-06-06

# Privacy – essence makeup

Here at Essence we’re always looking out for our friends, fans and consumer. Any information collected on our website is used to help us improve and deliver the best user experience. Here are all the details on what information is collected, how it is collected and how it is processed. All info that is collected will not be shared with other parties.

Privacy Policy of www.essencemakeup.com

This Application collects some Personal Data from its Users.

___________________________________________________________________________

## Data Controller and Owner

Cosnova, Inc. 55 5th Avenue, New York, NY 10003,  
customerservice@cosnova.com

## Types of Data collected

Among the types of Personal Data that this Application collects, by itself or through third parties, there are: Cookies, Usage data, first name, last name, phone number, email address and geographic position.

Other Personal Data collected may be described in other sections of this privacy policy or by dedicated explanation text contextually with the Data collection.

The Personal Data may be freely provided by the User, or collected automatically when using this Application.

Any use of Cookies - or of other tracking tools - by this Application or by the owners of third party services used by this Application, unless stated otherwise, serves to identify Users and remember their preferences, for the sole purpose of providing the service required by the User.

Failure to provide certain Personal Data may make it impossible for this Application to provide its services.

Users are responsible for any Personal Data of third parties obtained, published or shared through this Application and confirm that they have the third party's consent to provide the Data to the Owner.

## Mode and place of processing the Data

#### Methods of processing

The Data Controller processes the Data of Users in a proper manner and shall take appropriate security measures to prevent unauthorized access, disclosure, modification, or unauthorized destruction of the Data.

The Data processing is carried out using computers and/or IT enabled tools, following organizational procedures and modes strictly related to the purposes indicated. In addition to the Data Controller, in some cases, the Data may be accessible to certain types of persons in charge, involved with the operation of the site (administration, sales, marketing, legal, system administration) or external parties (such as third party technical service providers, mail carriers, hosting providers, IT companies, communications agencies) appointed, if necessary, as Data Processors by the Owner. The updated list of these parties may be requested from the Data Controller at any time.

#### Place

The Data is processed at the Data Controller's operating offices and in any other places where the parties involved with the processing are located. For further information, please contact the Data Controller.

#### Retention time

The Data is kept for the time necessary to provide the service requested by the User, or stated by the purposes outlined in this document, and the User can always request that the Data Controller suspend or remove the data.

#### The use of the collected Data

The Data concerning the User is collected to allow the Owner to provide its services, as well as for the following purposes: Analytics, Contacting the User, Handling payments, Location-based interactions, Managing contacts and sending messages, Access to third party services' accounts and Displaying content from external platforms.

The Personal Data used for each purpose is outlined in the specific sections of this document.

#### Facebook permissions asked by this Application

This Application may ask for some Facebook permissions allowing it to perform actions with the User's Facebook account and to retrieve information, including Personal Data, from it.

For more information about the following permissions, refer to the [Facebook permissions documentation](https://developers.facebook.com/docs/authentication/permissions/) and to the [Facebook privacy policy](https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/).

The permissions asked are the following:

**Basic information**

By default, this includes certain User’s Data such as id, name, picture, gender, and their locale. Certain connections of the User, such as the Friends, are also available. If the User has made more of their Data public, more information will be available.

**Status**

Provides access to the User's status messages and checkins.

## Detailed information on the processing of Personal Data

Personal Data is collected for the following purposes and using the following services:

#### Access to third party services' accounts **  
**

This type of services allows this Application to access Data from your account on a third party service and perform actions with it.

These services are not activated automatically, but require explicit authorization by the User.

#### Access to the Facebook account (This Application)

This service allows this Application to connect with the User's account on the Facebook social network, provided by Facebook, Inc.  
Permissions asked: Status.  
Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://www.facebook.com/policy.php)

#### Access to the Twitter account (Twitter, Inc.)

This service allows this Application to connect with the User's account on the Twitter social network, provided by Twitter, Inc.  
Personal Data collected: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service.

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://twitter.com/privacy)

## Analytics  

The services contained in this section enable the Owner to monitor and analyze web traffic and can be used to keep track of User behavior.

#### Google Analytics (Google Inc.)

Google Analytics is a web analysis service provided by Google Inc. (“Google”). Google utilizes the Data collected to track and examine the use of this Application, to prepare reports on its activities and share them with other Google services.

Google may use the Data collected to contextualize and personalize the ads of its own advertising network.  
Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage data.  
Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/) – [Opt Out](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en)

#### Google AdWords conversion tracking (Google Inc.)

Google AdWords conversion tracking is an analytics service provided by Google Inc. that connects data from the Google AdWords advertising network with actions performed on this Application.

Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data.

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/)

## Contacting the User  

#### Contact form (This Application)

By filling in the contact form with their Data, the User authorizes this Application to use these details to reply to requests for information, quotes or any other kind of request as indicated by the form’s header.

Personal Data collected: email address, first name, last name and phone number.

#### Mailing List or Newsletter (This Application)

By registering on the mailing list or for the newsletter, the User’s email address will be added to the contact list of those who may receive email messages containing information of commercial or promotional nature concerning this Application. Your email address might also be added to this list as a result of signing up to this Application or after making a purchase.

Personal Data collected: email address, first name and last name.

## Displaying content from external platforms  

This type of services allows you to view content hosted on external platforms directly from the pages of this Application and interact with them.

This type of service might still collect web traffic data for the pages where the service is installed, even when Users do not use it.

#### Google Maps widget (Google Inc.)

Google Maps is a maps visualization service provided by Google Inc. that allows this Application to incorporate content of this kind on its pages.

Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage data.

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.it/intl/en/policies/privacy/)

#### Typekit (Adobe Systems Incorporated)

Typekit is a typeface visualization service provided by Adobe Systems Incorporated that allows this Application to incorporate content of this kind on its pages.

Personal Data collected: Usage data and various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service.

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://www.adobe.com/privacy/typekit.html)

#### MyFonts (MyFonts Inc.)

MyFonts is a typeface visualization service provided by MyFonts Inc. that allows this Application to incorporate content of this kind on its pages.

Personal Data collected: Usage data and various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service.

Place of processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](http://www.myfonts.com/info/legal/#Privacy)

##  ****Handling payments

Payment processing services enable this Application to process payments by credit card, bank transfer or other means. To ensure greater security, this Application shares only the information necessary to execute the transaction with the financial intermediaries handling the transaction.

Some of these services may also enable the sending of timed messages to the User, such as emails containing invoices or notifications concerning the payment.

#### Apple Pay (Apple Inc.)

Apple Pay is a payment service provided by Apple Inc., which allows Users to make payments using their mobile phones.

Personal Data collected: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service.

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://www.apple.com/privacy/privacy-policy/)

#### PayPal (PayPal Inc.)

PayPal is a payment service provided by PayPal Inc., which allows Users to make online payments.

Personal Data collected: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service.

## Location-based interactions

#### Non-continuous geolocation (This Application)

This Application may collect, use, and share User location Data in order to provide location-based services.

Most browsers and devices provide tools to opt out from this feature by default. If explicit authorization has been provided, the User’s location data may be tracked by this Application.

The geographic location of the User is determined in a manner that isn't continuous, either at the specific request of the User or when the User doesn't point out its current location in the appropriate field and allows the application to detect the position automatically.

Personal Data collected: geographic position.

#### Managing contacts and sending messages

This type of services makes it possible to manage a database of email contacts, phone contacts or any other contact information to communicate with the User.

These services may also collect data concerning the date and time when the message was viewed by the User, as well as when the User interacted with it, such as by clicking on links included in the message.

#### MailChimp (The Rocket Science Group, LLC.)

MailChimp is an email address management and message sending service provided by The Rocket Science Group, LLC.

Personal Data collected: email address.

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/)

##  Remarketing and behavioral targeting

This type of service allows this Application and its partners to inform, optimize and serve advertising based on past use of this Application by the User.  
This activity is performed by tracking Usage Data and by using Cookies, information that is transferred to the partners that manage the remarketing and behavioral targeting activity.

#### Remarketing through Google Analytics for Display Advertising (Google Inc.)

Google Analytics for Display Advertising is a remarketing and behavioral targeting service provided by Google Inc. that connects the tracking activity performed by Google Analytics and its Cookies with the Adwords advertising network and the Doubleclick Cookie.

Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data.

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/) – [Opt Out](https://www.google.com/settings/ads/onweb/optout)

## Further information about Personal Data

#### Selling goods and services online

The Personal Data collected are used to provide the User with services or to sell goods, including payment and possible delivery.

The Personal Data collected to complete the payment may include the credit card, the bank account used for the transfer, or any other means of payment envisaged. The kind of Data collected by this Application depends on the payment system used.

## Additional information about Data collection and processing

#### Legal action

The User's Personal Data may be used for legal purposes by the Data Controller, in Court or in the stages leading to possible legal action arising from improper use of this Application or the related services.

The User declares to be aware that the Data Controller may be required to reveal personal data upon request of public authorities.

#### Additional information about User's Personal Data

In addition to the information contained in this privacy policy, this Application may provide the User with additional and contextual information concerning particular services or the collection and processing of Personal Data upon request.

#### System Logs and Maintenance

For operation and maintenance purposes, this Application and any third party services may collect files that record interaction with this Application (System Logs) or use for this purpose other Personal Data (such as IP Address).

#### Information not contained in this policy

More details concerning the collection or processing of Personal Data may be requested from the Data Controller at any time. Please see the contact information at the beginning of this document.

## The rights of Users

Users have the right, at any time, to know whether their Personal Data has been stored and can consult the Data Controller to learn about their contents and origin, to verify their accuracy or to ask for them to be supplemented, cancelled, updated or corrected, or for their transformation into anonymous format or to block any data held in violation of the law, as well as to oppose their treatment for any and all legitimate reasons. Requests should be sent to the Data Controller at the contact information set out above.

This Application does not support “Do Not Track” requests.

To determine whether any of the third party services it uses honor the “Do Not Track” requests, please read their privacy policies.

#### Changes to this privacy policy

The Data Controller reserves the right to make changes to this privacy policy at any time by giving notice to its Users on this page. It is strongly recommended to check this page often, referring to the date of the last modification listed at the bottom. If a User objects to any of the changes to the Policy, the User must cease using this Application and can request that the Data Controller removes the Personal Data. Unless stated otherwise, the then-current privacy policy applies to all Personal Data the Data Controller has about Users.

#### Information about this privacy policy

The Data Controller is responsible for this privacy policy, prepared starting from the modules provided by Iubenda and hosted on Iubenda's servers.

## Definitions and legal references

#### Personal Data (or Data)

Any information regarding a natural person, a legal person, an institution or an association, which is, or can be, identified, even indirectly, by reference to any other information, including a personal identification number.

#### Usage Data

Information collected automatically from this Application (or third party services employed in this Application), which can include: the IP addresses or domain names of the computers utilized by the Users who use this Application, the URI addresses (Uniform Resource Identifier), the time of the request, the method utilized to submit the request to the server, the size of the file received in response, the numerical code indicating the status of the server's answer (successful outcome, error, etc.), the country of origin, the features of the browser and the operating system utilized by the User, the various time details per visit (e.g., the time spent on each page within the Application) and the details about the path followed within the Application with special reference to the sequence of pages visited, and other parameters about the device operating system and/or the User's IT environment.

#### User

The individual using this Application, which must coincide with or be authorized by the Data Subject, to whom the Personal Data refers.

#### Data Subject

The legal or natural person to whom the Personal Data refers.

#### Data Processor (or Data Supervisor)

The natural person, legal person, public administration or any other body, association or organization authorized by the Data Controller to process the Personal Data in compliance with this privacy policy.

#### Data Controller (or Owner)

The natural person, legal person, public administration or any other body, association or organization with the right, also jointly with another Data Controller, to make decisions regarding the purposes, and the methods of processing of Personal Data and the means used, including the security measures concerning the operation and use of this Application. The Data Controller, unless otherwise specified, is the Owner of this Application.

#### This Application

The hardware or software tool by which the Personal Data of the User is collected.

#### Cookies

Small piece of data stored in the User's device.

#### Legal information

Notice to European Users: this privacy statement has been prepared in fulfillment of the obligations under Art. 10 of EC Directive n. 95/46/EC, and under the provisions of Directive 2002/58/EC, as revised by Directive 2009/136/EC, on the subject of Cookies.

This privacy policy relates solely to this Application.

Latest update: March 25, 2016
